<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Baris Kasikci</title>
 <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="/"/>
 <updated>2015-09-08T22:39:17-07:00</updated>
 <id></id>
 <author>
   <name>Baris Kasikci</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Bio</title>
   <link href="/2015/08/07/bio/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>/2015/08/07/bio</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Baris Kasikci is a fifth and final year PhD candidate in the Dependable Systems Laboratory &lt;a href=&quot;http://dslab.epfl.ch/&quot;&gt;(DSLAB)&lt;/a&gt; at EPFL, advised by &lt;a href=&quot;http://people.epfl.ch/george.candea&quot;&gt;George Candea&lt;/a&gt;. His research is centered around building techniques, tools and environments that will ultimately help us build more reliable and secure software. He is interested in finding solutions that will allow programmers to debug their code in an easier way. In this regard, he strives to find efficient ways to detect, classify and perform root cause diagnosis of bugs. He is also interested in efficient runtime instrumentation and program analysis under various memory models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Baris is one of the four recipients of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://labs.vmware.com/academic/vmware-2014-2015-graduate-fellowships&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;VMware 2014-2015 Graduate Fellowship&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During his PhD, Baris interned at Microsoft Research, VMware and Intel. Before starting his PhD, Baris worked as a software engineer for four years, mainly developing real time embedded systems software. Before joining EPFL, he was working for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.siemens.com/corporate-technology/en/index.php&quot;&gt;Siemens Corporate Technology&lt;/a&gt;. More details can be found in his &lt;a href=&quot;http://bariskasikci.org/cv.pdf&quot;&gt;CV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>News</title>
   <link href="/2015/08/06/news/"/>
   <updated>2015-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>/2015/08/06/news</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;http://dslab.epfl.ch/pubs/gist.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; on automated root cause diagnosis is accepted to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ssrc.ucsc.edu/sosp15/&quot;&gt;SOSP&amp;#39;15&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;http://dslab.epfl.ch/pubs/failure-sketches.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; on failure sketches is accepted to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usenix.org/conference/hotos15&quot;&gt;HotOS&amp;#39;15&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am serving as a reviewer for Transactions on Software Engineering &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.computer.org/web/tse&quot;&gt;(TOSEM&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am spending the summer 2015  at Intel working together with &lt;a href=&quot;http://cseweb.ucsd.edu/%7Ecpereira/&quot;&gt;Cristiano Pereira&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/gillespokam/home&quot;&gt;Gilles Pokam&lt;/a&gt; on new techniques for automated debugging and security applications of hardware tracing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
